homeguru.com.my 2019-04-14

# Privacy | PropertyGuru Malaysia

**[English](https://www.propertyguru.com.my/privacy) | [Bahasa Malaysia](https://www.propertyguru.com.my/privasi) version**  

_Last updated: February 27, 2019_

PropertyGuru Pte Ltd and/or PropertyGuru International (Malaysia) Sdn Bhd (" **we** " or " **us** " or “ **our** ”) is the operator of [http://www.propertyguru.com.my](http://www.propertyguru.com.my/) (the " **Website** ") and the PropertyGuru mobile applications (the “ **Apps** ”), and we are committed to safeguarding your personal data. We may also refer to “PropertyGuru Group” throughout this policy which shall include our subsidiary and affiliate companies.

This Privacy Policy (together with our Terms of Service <https://www.propertyguru.com.my/terms-of-service> and any other documents referred to in it) applies to all visitors, users and any party who access the Website, as well as the Apps, and any other way you may connect to or interact with us through the use of our products and services, hereinafter collectively referred to as “Services”.

This Privacy Policy explains and sets out how personal data that we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be used, processed or disclosed by us, including how certain information would be used to personalise advertising directed at you. This Privacy Policy also sets out the types of personal data we collect, how we keep it secure, as well as how you can access or alter your personal data stored by us.

Please read the following carefully to understand our policy and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

Unless restricted by applicable law, you agree and consent to us that any and all personal data relating to you collected by us or provided by you from time to time may be used, processed, and disclosed for such purposes and to such persons as set out in this Privacy Policy.

We will ask for your explicit consent before we process any sensitive personal information (where relevant) unless so permitted under the Personal Data Protection Act 2010. Sensitive personal information shall mean your physical or mental health or condition, your political opinions, your religious beliefs or other beliefs of a similar nature, the commission or alleged commission by you of any offence or any other personal data to be decided by the relevant Minister from time to time.

We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time by posting a revised version on the Website. While we endeavor to send an individual notice every time the policy is amended, you will be deemed to have acknowledged and agreed to the amended Privacy Policy if you continue to use the Website, the Apps or our Services after the changes have taken effect. You are reminded to check this Website from time to time for updates to this Privacy Policy.

**1\. COLLECTION OF PERSONAL DATA**

1.1 You can choose to browse the Website and the Apps without disclosing your personal data. You are not required to provide personal data as a condition of using the Website or the Apps. However, in the event you are required to provide us with your personal data and you choose not to or fail to provide us with the necessary personal data, we may not be able to provide the products and services which you intend to purchase or access through our Website or Apps, respond to your requests in cases where you contact us directly or process your personal data for any of the purposes pursuant to our policy.

If you provide us with any personal data of a third party including but not limited to information of your spouse, children, parents and/or authorised representatives you represent to us that such third party have consented to you providing their personal data to us for the purpose as set out in Section 2 and to any parties mentioned in Section 4 of this policy.

When you use our Services, we collect a variety of information from and about you, your devices, and your interaction with the Services. Some of this information identifies you directly or can be used to loosely identify you when combined with other data.

1.1 Information you willingly provide.

When using our Services, you may be asked to provide personal information about yourself, such as but not limited to your name, contact information, payment information, details about your home or properties you are interested in or financial information, in the following non-exhaustive circumstance:-

(a) when you carry out transactions with us on or in relation to the Website or the Apps;

(b) when you register an account with us on the Website or the Apps;

(c) when you contact our customer service or sales people by email, telephone, or in person, to resolve any issues that you may be facing or with inquiries or requests;

(d) when you subscribe to the services that we are providing on the Website or the Apps, or for our email notifications, and/or newsletters.

(e) when you correspond with a real estate professional (such as a real estate agent or broker, mortgage lender or loan officer, property manager, investor, homebuilder, or others) via the Services;

(f) when you complete other forms or transactions, such as a request for loan information or a rental housing and background check application;

(g) you may also provide information about a third party through the Services, for example, if you share a real estate listing with a recipient via email or sms. Some information you provide through our Services is collected and processed by third parties (such as google analytics) on our behalf; and/or

(h) when you use any of the Services offered on our Website.

1.3 Information we obtain from others.

For the purpose as set out in Section 2 of this policy, you acknowledge that we will receive and you agree and consent for us to retain and process such information obtained from authorised third party(ies) as disclosed in this policy. In respect of this, you consent that the generation of such information by the authorised third party(ies) may be based on information in their database.

1.4 Cookies, Pixels, and other tracking mechanisms.

We and our partners use various technologies to collect information automatically when you access and use our Services, including cookies, and other similar technologies. Cookies are bits of electronic information that can be transferred to your computer or other electronic device to uniquely identify your browser. When you use the Services, we and our partners may place one or more cookies on your computer or other electronic devices or use other technologies that provide similar functionality.

(a) We and our partners may use cookies to connect your activity on the Services with other information we store about you in your account profile or your prior interactions on our Services to, for example, store your preferences. The use of cookies helps us improve the quality of our Services to you, by identifying information which is most interesting to you, tracking trends, measuring the effectiveness of advertising, or storing information you may want to retrieve on a regular basis, such as your shortlisted properties or preferred searches. At any time, you may adjust settings on your browser to refuse cookies according to the instructions related to your browser. However, if you choose to disable cookies, many of the free features of the Services may not operate properly.

(b) Some of our pages may also include pixels, which are electronic files to count users who have visited that page, to track activity over time and across different websites, to determine users’ interactions with emails we send, to identify certain cookies on the computer or other electronic device accessing that page, or to collect other related information, and this information may be associated with your unique browser, device identifier, or IP address. We may, for example, implement a pixel on specific Services where you view a certain listing so that we can track whether the listing is of relevance to you while offering recommendations. Through these pixels and cookies we collect information about your use of our Services, including the type of browser you use, access times, pages viewed, your IP address and the page you visited before navigating to our Services.

(c) We also collect information about the computer or mobile device you use to access our Services, such as the hardware model, operating system and version, unique device identifiers, mobile network information, and browsing behavior.

(d) We also allow certain third parties to collect information about your online activities through cookies and other technologies when you use the Website or the Apps. These third parties include (a) business partners, who collect information when you view or interact with one of their advertisements on the Website or the Apps, and (b) advertising networks, who collect information about your interests when you view or interact with one of the advertisements they place on many different web sites on the Internet. The information gathered by these third parties are non-personally identifiable information which is used to make predictions about your characteristics, interests or preferences and to display advertisements on the Website, the Apps, and across the Internet which are tailored to your interests

(e) Many of the third parties we allow to collect information on the Website and the Apps are members of the Network Advertising Initiative, which offers a single location to opt out of advertising targeting from member companies. To opt out, please follow the link: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/> and follow the instructions on the site. Another good way of opting out is through the following link: <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>. Lastly, you can manage the type of cookies that are allowed through your browser settings, including completely blocking all cookies if you so wish. For information about how to manage cookies on your browser, please see the help section of the browser you are using.

1.5 Mobile device and mobile browser information.

You may adjust settings on your mobile device and mobile browser regarding cookies and sharing of certain information, such as your mobile device model or the language your mobile device uses, by adjusting the privacy and security settings on your mobile device. Please refer to the instructions provided by your mobile service provider or mobile device manufacturer.

1.6 Location Data.

If you enable location services on your mobile device, PropertyGuru Group with your permission may collect the location of your device, which we use to provide you with location-based information and advertising. If you wish to deactivate this feature, you can disable location services on your mobile device.

1.7 Email Management.

You may receive email from PropertyGuru Group for a variety of reasons - for example, if you took an action through the Services, you signed up for a regular report, or you posted your home for sale or rent and a buyer sent you a message. If you have an account with PropertyGuru Group, you may edit your preferences through your account settings. Also, you can manage your receipt of some types of communication by following the instructions included in the email we send to you. Please note that, even if you unsubscribe from certain email correspondences, we may still need to email you with important transactional or administrative information.

**2\. PURPOSES OF USE**

2.1 The personal data which you provide may be used and processed by us and/or any parties as mentioned in Section 4 of this policy without any reference back to you whatsoever in the aggregate or individually and may be combined with other information, the scope of which may include, but not limited to the following:

(a) administering, managing or operating the Website and the Apps;

(b) to verify your identity, update our records and generally maintain your account with us;

(c) improving your browsing experience by personalising the Website and the Apps;

(d) enabling your use of the services available on the Website and the Apps;

(e) providing to you the products and services that you have specifically requested;

(f) responding to your enquiries or requests pursuant to your emails and/or submission of form(s) on the Website or the Apps;

(g) responding to and taking follow-up action on complaints regarding the use of the Website, the Apps or any product or service provided by us;

(h) sending you general (non-marketing) commercial communications;

(i) performing office and operational administrative matters;

(j) providing third parties with statistical information about our users. Such statistical information may be used to personalise advertising on the Website or the Apps, but cannot be used to identify any individual user. For details on how to opt out of personalised advertising, please refer to section 8 of this Privacy Policy;

(k) providing our affiliates and/or business partners or persons for any reasons whatsoever;

(l) Analyze your content and other information (including instant messages, photos, attachments, and other communications);

(m) conduct research and support innovation;

(n) create analytics and reports for external parties, including partners, publishers, advertisers, apps, third-parties and the public regarding the use of and trends within our Services and ads, including showing trends to partners regarding general preferences, the effectiveness of ads and information on user experiences. These analytics and reports may include aggregate or pseudonymized information;

(o) provide location-based Services, advertising, search results, and other content consistent with your location settings;

(p) detect and defend against fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful activity;

(q) data processing purposes;

(r) provide third party(ies) with your personal data for the provision of Services to you;

(s) profile your personal data to conduct survey, create targeted market campaign and product infographic; and/or

(t) matching your personal data and/or information in relation to you for other purposes in connection with the provision or offering of products and services, whether by us or other third parties, including but not limited to:-

(i) recommend properties to you;

(ii) submit your personal data to partnering banks or developer and/or agent for loan or mortgage loan application on behalf of you;

(iii) recommend financial products to you;

(iv) share your personal data and/or information in relation to you with other financial institution, financial services providers and/or coaches to customise financial products or conduct workshops and/or courses.

2.2 We may also be required to disclose your personal data to third parties for the following purposes:

(a) to comply with any legal requirement;

(b) to enforce or apply our Terms of Service <https://www.propertyguru.com.my/terms-of-service> and other agreements;

(c) to protect our rights, property, and safety, and the rights, property and safety of the PropertyGuru Group, other users of the Website or the Apps, and others;

(d) in connection with any legal proceedings or prospective legal proceedings; and

(e) in connection with a business asset transaction (i.e. the purchase, sale, lease, merger or amalgamation or any other acquisition, disposal or financing of an organisation or a portion of an organisation or of any of the business or assets of an organisation) to which we are a party or a prospective party.

2.1 We will disclose personal data you have provided to third parties for the purposes of direct marketing.

2.2 You can withdraw your consent by contacting us, our contact details can be found at section 12 below.

**3\. SECURITY**

3.1 We will take reasonable technical and organizational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse, unauthorized or accidental access or disclosure, destruction or alteration of your personal data.

3.2 While we shall store all the personal data you provide on secure servers in an encrypted format and strive to protect your personal data, you understand that the transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure. As such, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal data transmitted to the Website or the Apps and any transmission is at your own risk.

3.3 Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of the Website or the Apps, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone. We will NEVER ask you for your password other than when you log in to the Website or the Apps, as the case may be.

3.4 We urge you to take steps to keep your personal information safe, such as choosing a strong password and keeping it private, as well as logging out of your user account, and closing your web browser when finished using our services on a shared or unsecured device.

**4\. DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL DATA**

4.1 We will keep the personal data that you disclose confidential subject at all times to the privacy laws applicable to us. Nonetheless, you agree and consent to us that such personal data may be provided to the following categories of parties for the purposes set out in section 2 of this policy:-

(a) any person to whom we are compelled or required to do so under law or in response to a legitimate instruction from a competent or government agency;

(b) to any of PropertyGuru Group (which may be in or outside Malaysia);

(c) to such parties as we or our affiliates may be required by legal process or pursuant to any other foreign or domestic legal, regulatory, stock exchange, clearing house or self-regulatory body obligation or request, or agreement entered into by any of them and any governmental authority, domestic or foreign, or between or amongst any two or more domestic or foreign governmental authorities or other authorities, including disclosure to courts, tribunals, legal, regulatory, tax and government authorities, stock exchanges, clearing houses and self regulatory bodies;

(d) any parties authorized by you;

(e) where applicable, third parties who provide related services or products in connection with our business such as insurance agencies/insurers;

(f) government agencies, statutory authorities and industry regulators;

(g) our external auditors, consultants, accountants, lawyers or other financial or professional advisers;

(h) any credit bureau, credit reporting agencies and credit reference agencies and the relevant subscribers of the credit reporting agencies and credit reference agencies;

(i) any liquidator, receiver, official assignee or any person appointed under applicable law or court order relating to bankruptcy, liquidation, winding up in respect of any individual or company; or

(j) our sub-contractors or third party service or product providers as we may determine to be necessary or appropriate.

**5\. WITHDRAWAL OF CONSENT**

5.1 Where we have relied on your consent for the processing of your personal data, you have the right to withdraw consent to the processing of your personal data at any time to the extent that such withdrawal does not conflict with any of our legal obligations.

5.2 Should you wish to withdraw your consent, please e-mail to us and our contact details can be found at section 12 below.

5.3 Upon receiving your completed withdrawal consent and your identity as the subject of the personal data has been verified, we will process your request for withdrawal of consent, and will thereafter cease to process your personal data in the manner stated in your request. In the event we are unable to verify your identity as the subject of the personal data, we will contact you at the contact given to us in the form.

5.4 Please be informed that in the event you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to continue to provide the Services to you and this may result in the termination of your existing relationship and/or agreement with us. In respect of this, our legal rights and remedies in such event are expressly reserved.

**6\. UPDATE OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

6.1 It is important that your personal data provided to is accurate, complete, not misleading and kept up-to date. As such, you shall update your personal data in the event you believe that your personal data in our possession is inaccurate, incomplete, misleading or out of date. We will not be responsible for relying on inaccurate, incomplete, misleading and out of date personal data if you fail to update us of the latest changes.

6.2 You may access and update your personal data within our Services any time by accessing <https://www.propertyguru.com.my/user-profile>.

**7\. INTERNATIONAL DATA TRANSFERS**

7.1 Our facilities and servers may be located in other jurisdictions outside of Malaysia and pursuant to such circumstances, your personal data may temporarily be stored, processed or transferred outside of Malaysia between any of the countries in which we operate in order to enable us to use your personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service <https://www.propertyguru.com.my/terms-of-service>. As such, you hereby expressly agree and consent to us for the transfer of your personal data outside of Malaysia for such purposes. Please note that these entities may be established in countries that might not offer a level of data protection that is equivalent to that offered in Malaysia under the laws of Malaysia.

7.2 Notwithstanding section 7.1 above, we will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your personal data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**8\. THIRD PARTY WEBSITES**

8.1 The Website and the Apps may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks and vendors. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

**9\. ACCESS AND CORRECTION**

9.1 Our Data Protection officer is responsible for ensuring that requests for access to personal data and amendment of personal data are properly dealt with in accordance with the procedures specified herein. Please be informed that we may charge you the applicable fee for the handling and processing of your request for access to personal data.

All requests for information or requests for the amendment of information held by us shall be made by completing our standard Request for Information/Amendment of Information form (PDF available here at <http://www.propertyguru.com.sg/customer-service/privacy/request-form>, and sending a copy of the duly completed form to us, our contact details can be found at section 12 below.

9.2 Please note that we will only accept and act on requests that comply with this Privacy Policy. Any request that does not comply with the above will be rejected, and we will not take any action in relation to such rejected requests.

9.3 We may refuse to disclose or amend any personal data for the reasons set out in the Personal Data Protection Act 2012. In the event we refuse to disclose or amend any personal data upon your request, we shall provide you the reasons of our refusal.

9.4 As far as reasonably possible, we will respond to your request within ten (10) working days from the date of receipt of the request. If that is not possible, you will be so notified within ten (10) working days from the date of receipt of the request.

**10\. RETENTION OF PERSONAL DATA**

10.1 All personal data in our possession will be retained as long as necessary, required to satisfy legal regulatory and accounting requirements, as is relevant for the purposes for which it was collected or to protect our interests.

10.2 We will exercise measures to cease to retain, anonymise your personal data or remove the means by which the personal data can be associated with you, as soon as it is reasonable to assume that the retention of personal data (i) is no longer required for the purpose (as informed to your in Section 2 above) for which the personal data is being collected; or (ii) it is no longer necessary for any legal or business purpose.

10.3 For the avoidance of doubt, in the event you cease to use our Services on our Website or App, we may continue storing, using and/or disclosing your personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy and our legal obligations.

**11\. DISCLAIMER**

11.1 We shall not be liable for any voluntary disclosure of personal data by you to other users in connection with the use of the Website or the Apps, as the case may be.

11.2 We shall not be liable for any disclosure of personal data due to any reason whatsoever including but not limited to all attempted or actual acts of terrorist, acts of God or any circumstances beyond our control and/or in the absence of any gross negligence or wilful misconduct on our part.

**12\. CONTACT US**

12.1 For any enquiries or request, please do not hesitate to contact our privacy officer:-

(a) by way of e-mail at [dpo@propertyguru.com.sg](mailto:dpo@propertyguru.com.sg);

(b) by way of post at:-

**PropertyGuru International (Malaysia) Sdn. Bhd.**  
Unit E-11-2&3, Menara Suezcap 2,  
KL Gateway, No. 2, Jalan Kerinchi,  
Gerbang Kerinchi Lestari,  
59200 Kuala Lumpur  
Attention: Privacy Officer; and/or

(c) by way of telephone call at (+ 60) 3 7932 7555.

**13\. CONFLICT**

13.1 In the event of conflict between the English and Bahasa Melayu versions of the Privacy Policy, the English version of the Privacy Policy shall prevail.
